我什么也看不到
I've never seen so much nothing.
我也未曾白跑这么远过
I've never walked so far to see it.
我也不知道怎么就知道
How was I to know the only structures on this planet
这个星球上的生物就在星际之门附近
would be in the immediate area around the stargate?
就在那儿
There's the gate.
马上开启它
Dial it up.
等等，能量表显示这里的读数
和一英里前的一样
Wait. The energy readings here are exactly
the same as they were a mile away.
我认为我们应该停下来检查一下
I really think we should stay a while.
我想你是讨厌穿上这身衣服吧
I thought you hated wearing these suits.
确实讨厌，身上很不舒服
可是能量表的读数太奇怪了
I do. I'm incredibly uncomfortable,
but these energy readings are amazing.
看来有些东西在我们周围啊
It's like it's coming from all around us.
你还无法对此解释吧？
And yet you cannot explain it.
不见得
Not yet.
你不是不知道如何用这东西吧？
You can't figure out a way we can use it?
不见得
Not yet.
好吧
All right.
什么乱七八糟的
Then let's call it a mission.
别，别，别啊
有一种叫纯科学的东西
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
There is such a thing as pure science.
不是所有的成功马上都可以拿来用的
Not everything has to be immediately useful.
要知道，你说服我到这里来的根据
You talked me into coming here because you thought
仅仅是因为你认为能量表的读数显示
这里可能存在外星文明
those energy readings indicated
the presence of a civilization.
而这里没有建筑，没有生物，什么都没有
There are no buildings, no people, no nothing.
只有雾
Just fog.
严格的说这不是雾
It's not technically fog.
空气中并没有水蒸气
There's no actual water vapor in the atmosphere.
我的意思是
I mean, for that matter,
我认为我们没必要戴这个头罩
I don't think we need to wear the hazmat gear.
现在我告诉你
Now you tell me.
把门打开
Dial the gate.
我们回去吧
Let's move out.
等等，等等，在等会
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Hold on.
你想留这儿
You wanted useful.
你说什么呀？
What are you talking about?
当虫洞联通的时候
When the wormhole connected,
能量场的读数有了很大的变化
there was a wild fluctuation in the energy field.
如果我没有搞错的话
I mean, if I'm reading these numbers right,
看来星际之门是从这里的空气中
吸取能量的
it looks like the gate is actually
drawing power from the atmosphere.
那又如何？
So?
据我所知，这个能量场绵延数英里
To the best of my knowledge, this field goes on for miles.
我的意思是，可能覆盖了整个星球
I mean, for all we know, envelops the entire planet.
我们身边就可能存在大量生物
We're talking about a lot of energy here.
大量生物是什么意思？
How much is a lot?
以焦耳或尔格的形式存在
（焦耳，尔格均为能量单位）
Well, in terms of joules or ergs?
以什么形式存在？还很多？
In terms of... lots.
是的，很多
Well, lots and lots.
多得足够打开一个通往地球的虫洞
Enough to open a wormhole back to Earth.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第9集 回家
Season 1 : Episode 9
Home
我觉得亚特兰蒂斯之门是唯一一个可
让我们返回地球的入口
I thought the atlantis gate was
the only one capable of dialing Earth.
是的，可那是因为它是唯一一个
有着能量水晶球的地方
It is, but that's because it's the only one
with an additional control crystal
只要我们拥有它
它产生的能量足以让我们回去
that allows an eighth chevron to lock.
可能是出于安全的原因？
It's probably a security measure.
这没关系的
It doesn't matter.
只要我们得到能量控制水晶球
As long as we have the control crystal,
我就有办法让其他星际之门运作起来
I can make the other gate work.
你的意思是我们将DHD从这里带到
You're suggesting we remove it from our DHD
M5S224上去
and bring it to M5S224?
是的
Yes.
有没有风险？
应该没问题的
- Isn't that risky?
- I'll be fine.
我想她是要毁掉我们现在的星际之门
I think she means in terms of breaking our own gate.
我知道我在做什么
I know what I'm doing.
再说，水晶球要是没有足够能量的话是毫无用处的
Besides, the control crystal
is useless without enough power.
可你说你不知道
能力从何而来啊？
You said you didn't know
where the energy was coming from.
我相信能量来自于
I believe it is being generated somehow
这里的空气中
in the atmosphere itself.
雾？
The fog?
是的
Yes.
可你说这不是雾啊？
You said it wasn't fog.
管他是什么呢
Whatever it is.
你怎么知道呢？
Well, how do you know?
我也不知道
I don't yet,
可是这雾，或者水汽
不管你叫它什么
but the fog, or the mist,
or whatever you want to call it,
是这数英里内仅有的东西
同时能量表的读数也一直保持恒定
is the only thing around for miles,
and the energy readings were constant.
好的，即使你能搞清楚这件事
Okay, even if you can pull this off,
我们恐怕还得假设地球上
we have to assume that the Earth gate
那通往神马星球的虫洞
lacks a power source capable of establishing
还是缺少足够的能量来发挥作用
a wormhole back to Pegasus.
所以不管谁回去
So whoever went,
可能要冒个风险
也就是说这可能是个单程的履行
it'd be taking the risk
that it might be a one-way trip.
我肯定有人会愿意冒这个险的
I'm sure someone will volunteer.
你？
You?
不管你们相信如何，只要我知道还有
一丝机会回来的话，我也会选择回去
Believe it or not, I would only go if I knew
there was a good chance I could come back.
至少我们可以给地上的长官带个信
At least, we can send a message to Stargate Command.
让他们知道我们现在的情况还不错
Let them know we're okay.
我们已收集了很多的资料
We've gathered a lot of intel.
如果可能的话，我们应当把他们
发回去
We should send it... if we can.
即使通过无线电也好
Even if it's over a radio.
好了
That's it.
不知道把它安在
So how easy will it be to put that thing
其他地方会不会很容易
in the other DHD?
亚特兰蒂斯的能量场是很独特的
The atlantis' DHD is unique.
它不像一个空着的插槽
等着我们往里面查东西
It's not like the'll be an empty slot
waiting for us to plug it in.
你的意思是？
Meaning?
我的意思是可能还需要一些其他的
辅助部件
Meaning that there may be some disassembly required.
你要把它带走
You want to take the DHD apart?
我会重新把它放回去的
I'll put it back together again.
你能不能别冒这个险去拆除其他的星际之门
Do you not run the risk of disabling the other Stargate?
除非我翘辫子了
否则的话不大可能
Only if I screw up, which is extremely unlikely.
840年
840 years.
什么？
What?
这就是我们坐飞船去那里
That's how long it will take us
要花的时间
to come get you by puddle jumper.
虽然这样，你们仍然会这么做的，对吧？
But you would do that, right?
当然我们会这么做
Of course we would.
唉，没必要这么做了
Well, it won't be necessary.
不过，我可否申请带个帮手
However, I may require some assistance.
少校？
Major?
中尉？
Lieutenant?
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
亚特兰蒂斯，这是McKay
Atlantis, this is McKay.
说吧
Go ahead.
我们已准备好了要拆除DHD
We're ready to begin work on the DHD.
你对此有把握吗，Rodney？
You're sure about this, Rodney?
是的，下次你听到我的呼叫时
肯定会听到好消息的
Positive. The next time you hear from us,
we'll be delivering the good news.
祝你好运
Good luck.
可能的话，我们回来吃晚饭
We'll be back  in time for supper.
好的
All right.
开始吧
Let's get started.
进来
Come in.
你好，有时间聊会吗？
Hi. Do you have a moment?
有啊
Yeah, sure.
“战争与和平”
"War and peace."
呵，大部头的书啊
That's some heavy reading.
是啊，在地球上准备这次任务时
Yep, back on Earth, when I was getting ready
我就曾想到可能在执行任务的期间
会有空闲时间
for this mission, I realized there was a good chance
用来读读书
that I might be here for a while,
所以我想，干嘛不带本书去呢
so I figured why not bring along a book
消遣一下也好嘛
that takes a while to read.
17页
Page 17.
我才开始读呢
I'm right on schedule.
我想和你谈谈这个，回家如何？
That's kind of what I wanted to talk to you about, home.
回家？
Going home.
哦
Oh.
McKay是对的
McKay is right.
只要这办法行得通
就可以搭起通往地球的虫洞
If this works, and we are able
to establish a wormhole back to Earth--
你知道，要是还继续讨论这个话题的话
我知道会讨论些什么
You know, if this conversation
is going where I think it's headed,
你不必在说了
you can put your mind at rest.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我书还没读完呢
I haven't read my book.
我要说你是向Hammond将军汇报的
Look, all I'm saying is that you are the person
最佳人选
who is best qualified to brief General Hammond
而且可以很好得解释幽灵将会给我们带来什么样的的危险
and the other powers that be about the Wraith threat.
呃，也许吧
Well, maybe so...
可是我认为这儿需要我
But I think I'm needed here.
好样的
Good.
可是要是你愿意回去的话，我可以理解
But if you want to go, I understand that, too.
你说什么，这里不需要我吗？
What are you saying, I'm not needed here?
我说我会理解的
I said I'd understand.
那谢谢了，可是我曾许诺过
一定要完成任务的
Well, thank you, but I made a commitment.
当然，可是这里的所谓外星生物
Of course, in all fairness, life-sucking aliens
并不是在我们的计划之中的啊
weren't part of the brochure.
不管如何，我会留在这儿的
Regardless, I'm staying.
好的
Good.
没有你的话，这儿真不知会变得怎样
Wouldn't be the same without you.
要是能搞好的话，你想不想回去？
So if this works, would you want to go back?
我不认为回去很重要
I don't think it matters what I would want.
为什么不？
Why not?
因为亚特兰蒂斯需要我啊
Because Atlantis can't afford to lose me.
我是星际理论，虫洞物理学最前沿的
科学家啊
I'm their foremost expert in gate theory,
wormhole physics,
而且我发现了许多被其他科学家们所忽视
and a myriad of other sciences too numerous to mention
而又非常重要的东西
yet too important to ignore.
我想见我奶奶
I'd love to see my grandma.
她可能会认为我还在阿富汗执行任务呢
She thinks I'm somewhere in afghanistan or something.
换句话说，要是有人回去的话
On the other hand, if anyone's going,
一定要得到SGC的尊重
it should be someone
that commands the respect of the SGC
要有耐心，有学识，有决心
and yet has the patience, knowledge, and determination
让他们带一队人过来
to bring them up to speed and
find a way to bring the cavalry back here.
你的意思是，你在哪里都是不可或缺的喽
So, what you're saying is you're invaluable everywhere.
当然，要是我走了的话，这里就没人能干活了
Granted, it would create a void if I were to go,
可是你们可以乘机好好休息
我会在那边设法
but you can all take comfort in the knowledge
that I'll be on the other side,
带一对援兵过来的
spearheading the effort to return with reinforcements,
还有给养，衣服什么的
fresh supplies, and big macs for all.
听你这么一说，我感觉好多了
I feel better already.
嗯，好
Yeah, good.
Sheppard少校
Major Sheppard!
你有没有接收到McKay博士发回的讯息
Have we heard back from Dr. McKay?
还没有
Not yet.
基地上传言已有了新的发现
Word of the discovery has
already spread throughout the base.
我注意到了
I've noticed.
当然了，这是意料之中的事情
It is to be expected, of course--
马上就要回到亲人的身边
faced with prospect of being reunited with loved ones,
回到熟悉的地面
returning to familiar ground.
是啊，我真想回去啊
Yeah, I'd love to go back.
你会考虑离开亚特兰蒂斯？
You would consider leaving Atlantis?
我只是希望我能再次回来
I just wish I knew I could gate back here.
激动一下也不错嘛
Then I'd go in a heartbeat.
回到自己所属的世界可是一个大好事啊
It would be wonderful to see your world.
汇报的时候你可以在一边帮我的
You could help me with the briefing.
乐意效劳
I would like that.
嘿，你对天马星的了解可比任何人都详细啊
Hey, you know more about
the Pegasus galaxy than anyone.
谈谈地球上的有趣的东西吧
Then there's all those
cool Earth things I've talked about,
比如说足球，观光览车等等
football, ferris wheels...
哦
Oh!
你还记得我们最后一次吃苞米花的情景吗？
Do you remember the last of the popcorn we ate?
我们本该再多吃点的
We can get more.
可要是知道还会回去的话
If we knew we could return.
异常启动
Unscheduled activation!
这是McKay博士发回的讯息
It's a radio transmission from Dr. McKay.
Rodney？
Rodney?
Elizabeth
Elizabeth.
我搞定了
I'm done.
正如你所见的那样，部件已安装上DHD
The component's installed
in the DHD, and as you can see--
好样的
Well done.
可是，能量读数有没有什么变化？
Sorry, what about the energy readings?
哦，和以前一样
Oh, same as before.
所有迹象显示，星际之门从空气中汲取能量
All indications are that the gate's
drawing power from the atmosphere,
能量足可以一次送八个人
and there's enough for an eight-chevron lock.
你在那儿别走
Okay, you stay put.
我们马上过来
好的
- We're on our way.
- Great.
现在我们，准备好了？
So are we, uh, ready?
准备什么？
What's there to be ready for?
呃，这可是件大事啊
Well, this is a big moment,
我们已经好久没和地面联系了
and I thought we haven't been
in contact for some time--
我们准备好了
开始吧
- We're ready.
- Go ahead.
快点启动啊
Please work.
星际之门总部，我是亚特兰蒂斯探险任务的
Stargate command, this is Dr. Elizabeth Weir
Elizabeth Weir博士
of the Atlantis expedition.
能听到我说话吗？
Do you read?
在重复一遍，我是Weir博士
I repeat, this is Dr. Weir.
请回答
Come in, please.
我是星际之门总部的Harriman中士
This is sergeant Harriman of Stargate Command.
不管你是谁，希望不要开玩笑
Whoever you are, this better not be a joke.
这不是玩笑，中士
No joke, sergeant.
我马上发送个人编号让你确认
I'm sending my personal IDC for confirmation.
刚才对不起了，Weir博士
Sorry about that, Dr. Weir.
忽然收到你们的讯息真令人感到惊奇
We're just a little surprised to be hearing from you.
可以理解
Understandable.
同道已经打开
The iris is open.
你们可以过来了
You're clear to come through.
谢谢，可是我们还不想冒险来个单程旅行
Thanks, but we're not ready to risk a one-way trip.
你不明白，博士
You don't understand, doctor.
这边情况有变
Things have changed around here.
从仙宫座到普洛米休斯的通道已经搭好
The asgard are in the process of fitting Prometheus
其能量足以到达其他的星系
with engines capable of reaching other galaxies.
我们正打算派人来找你们呢
We were manning a mission
to find out what happened to you.
他说的是真的么？
Is he serious?
你说的是真的？
Are you serious?
是的，长官
es, ma'am.
现在过来吧，一个月之内你就可以再回到天马座了
Come through now, and you could
be back in Pegasus inside of a month.
好的
Well...
谁去？
Who's going?
欢迎回到地球
Welcome back to Earth.
天马座星系确实存在许多的危险
And while the Pegasus galaxy does hold many dangers,
我想我们有必要考虑
I feel its potential rewards
justify the risk of maintaining
留在亚特兰蒂斯基地的必要性
a continued presence on the Atlantis base.
不幸的是，博士，你的报告递交国防部后
Unfortunately, doctor, your preliminary report
引起了他们很大的震惊
has given the Pentagon cause for concern.
如果幽灵的力量正像你们所说的那么强大的话
If the Wraith are as powerful as you say,
那他们就是比Goa’uld还要危险的敌人了
that would make them an enemy
even more dangerous than the Goa'uld.
有人认为我们有必要减轻我们的损失
There are those who believe it would be prudent
必要的情况下可以放弃整个天马星系
to cut our losses and abandon
the Pegasus galaxy all together.
将军，你不能——
General, you can't--
我们在谈论一种族类
他们曾击败过远古的人累
We are talking about a race that defeated the Ancients.
多年来，星际之门总部曾受到过
Over its years in operation,
Stargate Command has encountered
多次可能会毁灭地球的危险
a number of threats that could well have brought
about the destruction of this world.
可是，那些危险从未使你放弃
Now, that never stopped you from continuing
继续派人进行探险，将军
to send teams through the gate, General.
SG－1已经完成任务安全返回了
By the time SG-1 had returned from their first mission,
可是同时也造成了损失
the damage had already been done.
Goa’uld已经意识到我们的存在了
We'd alerted the Goa'uld to our presence
结束探险项目什么都改便不了
and shutting down operations
wouldn't have changed that.
可是，在幽灵这个问题上，我们仍有选择的余地
In the case of the Wraith, however, we have a choice.
也就是说我们要夹着尾巴逃跑喽
So we're just going to turn tail and run?
国防部会把这视为“战略撤退”
The Pentagon would prefer
to call it "a strategic withdrawal."
可是我们如何保证他们不会尾随我们而来？
But how can we be sure they won't come after us?
将军，他是对的
She's right, General.
他们以生命为食，现在他们知道地球上可以
够他们饱餐一顿了
They feed on human life forms, and now they know
there's a smorgasbord waiting for them here.
我认为我们没有选择的余地
I don't think we have a choice.
我们需要继续进行探索
We need to continue to explore the opportunities
探索天马座可能存在的高科技成功
for technological advancement
Pegasus galaxy has to offer,
更别提我们对那里存在的其他生物负有
不可推卸的责任
not to mention our responsibility
to the other humans who live there.
责任？
Responsibility?
是我们唤醒了幽灵
We did wake up the Wraith,
确实，我们要不去的话，这种事情最终仍会发生
and while, yes, that would've happened
eventually without our interference,
可是我们对古老科技的掌握使得我们
有责任保护那里的人
our access to ancient technology puts us in
a unique position to help those people.
我们不能就这样走了
We can't just walk away.
我只能向你说你们的建议
Rest assured your recommendation
会被送到政府最高层去研究的
will be given consideration at the highest level.
将军
General, sir!
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
Sheppard少校
Major Sheppard.
汇报这么快就完了，真令人惊奇啊
I'm surprised the briefing went as quickly as it did.
少校，你很直率
You were very thorough, Major.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
我想你该好好修养一阵子了
I thought you'd be enjoying some well-deserved R and R.
我正打算要出去待一阵子
I was just going to arrange some transportation, sir.
好好想想去哪儿，少校，哪儿都行
Consider it taken care of, Major. Anywhere you'd like.
啊，你真好
Well, that's very generous.
小伙子，你为国家作出了这么大的贡献
You've done your country a great service, son.
你应得的
You deserve it.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
我们的病号怎么样了？
Well, how's our patient doing?
少校，我们都检查完了
她可以走了
We're all done, Major.
She's free to go.
我还担心你会抛弃我呢
I was afraid you had abandoned me.
我正想带你出去呢
Just setting up our ride.
这样啊，那我们去哪儿？
So... where are we going?
走前要先给你打扮一下
We should start by getting you a new outfit.
你好，Simon
Hello, Simon.
哦，我的上帝
Oh, my god.
你什么时候......
When did you...
我想你
I missed you.
你没有新的留言
You have no new messages.
肯定别人打来的时候停电了
Hmm, must've been a power failure or something.
管他呢......
Anyways...
你的电视并没有任何问题
...there is nothing wrong with your television set.
请不要调整画面
Do not attempt to adjust the picture.
我们控制着电视的直播
We are controlling the transmission...
如果我们想它声音大一点的话
我们会加大音量
If we wish to make it louder,
we will bring up the volume.
如果我们想它声音变柔和一点的话
我们会......
If we wish to make it softer, we will tune...
你好
Hi.
谢谢你，少校
Thank you, Major.
不用谢
You're welcome.
我光顾过许多不同的世界的超市
I have traded in many market places on many worlds--
是国家，国家.....
Countries. Countries...
哦，当然，是国家
yes, of course. Countries...
但是这儿有这么多的东西供选购
But here there are so many
different items to choose from.
似乎你在这儿很开心
Yeah, you seemed like you were having fun,
而且一直逛了好几个小时
hours... And hours of fun.
终于挑到一套这么漂亮的衣服
But you picked out a nice outfit.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you.
我在想......
I wonder...
要是我们从未遇到过幽灵的话
If we had never suffered the Wraith,
我们还会不会将这种东西视为另一种文明呢
would my people have created
a civilization such as this?
我开始对一些事情产生了怀疑了
I'm starting to wonder about a few things myself.
你说什么？
What?
你没有任何问题？
Nothing feels wrong to you?
我不是指一件事情
I don't mean one thing.
我的意思是，所有的事情
I mean... everything.
我不明白
I do not understand.
对不起，呃
Excuse me, uh...
麻烦你带我们去绿苔公园好吗？
Could you take us to the Green Moss park area?
没问题
Sure thing.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想一旦我们到那儿后就会
搞清楚到底是什么困扰着我们
I think I'll have a better idea of
what's bothering me once we get there.
嘿，Sedge
Hey, Sedge!
你想我吗？
Did you miss me?
想到不能再想了
More than you can imagine.
我不知道曾看了多少次你走前留给我的录像带
I don't know how many times
I watched that damn tape you left me.
我早想亲自跟你谈谈
I wanted to tell you in person.
不会吧，你不会的
No, you didn't.
你担心我会跟你说这事
You were afraid I'd talk you out of it.
是的
I was afraid you'd try.
当你告诉我你要走
When you told me you were going away,
而且不便告诉我去哪儿的时候
我第一想到的是去韩国
but couldn't say where, my first guess was Korea.
其次想到的是去以色列
My second guess was Israel.
老实说，根本没想过你要去天马星系
To be honest, the Pegasus galaxy didn't make my list.
对不起
I am sorry.
我理解
I know.
我想你不会告诉我
I imagine my security clearance doesn't let you tell me
你们在那儿干些什么吧
what you've been doing while you were there--
不会
No.
或者是你们什么时候再次去那儿？
Or when you'll be leaving again?
不会
No.
哦，不过至少你能向我保证
Well, at the very least, you could promise me that...
你会带上这个的
You'll take this with you.
Simon
Simon.
真漂亮啊
It's beautiful.
看上去不错
Looks nice.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了？
Is something wrong?
你知道吗？对不起
刚才你亲我的时候......
You know what? I'm sorry.
It's just when you kissed me...
你在说些什么呀，Elizabeth？
What are you talking about, Elizabeth?
你好
Hello?
将军，什么——
General. What--
好的，我明白了
Yes, I understand.
谢谢
Thank you.
等会
Hang on!
哦，你好
Oh, hey.
刚睡着
Just the middle of a power nap, and...
瞧，裤子还没来得及穿呢
I'm not wearing any pants.
简直不敢相信你知道我住这儿
I didn't even think you knew where I lived.
空军告诉我的
Air Force.
这样啊
Oh, right.
哦，你看，我不能......
Oh, look, I can't, um...
实际上......
Really, um...
我和302室的姑娘有个约会
I have a date with a girl in 302.
她一直养了只猫
She's been taking care of the cat
在我不在的时候
很显然，她很想念我
for the whole time I was away,
and, apparently, she misses me...
Rodney
我知道，我会设法将猫赶走的
- Rodney...
- I know, I'm trying to pawn off my cat
然后......
off on a neighbor, and I end up with...
怎么了？
What?
我刚接到Hammond将军打来的电话
I just got a call from General Hammond.
普洛米休斯星球出事了
There was an accident on the Prometheus.
我们无法回到亚特兰蒂斯了
We can't go back to Atlantis.
我刚回家好好休息了一下
I was going to come home, get some rest,
现在精神百倍地回来工作
准备如何解决这个问题
then come back refreshed and
ready to work on a solution,
看是一个小时前，我突然明白
就像在浴池中的Archimedes一样
but an hour ago, it hit me,
like Archimedes in the bathtub--
顿悟了！尽管我不在浴池里
Eureka! Except I wasn't in a bathtub.
我在沙发上看着我的书
I was on a couch watching
a very strange  outer limits episode...
先别提Prometheus
Forget Prometheus.
我已经想出如何搭起一个虫洞了
I've figured out how to
establish a wormhole connection
以便回到天马座星系去
可是我需要ZPM
back to the Pegasus galaxy,
but I'm going to need the ZPM.
可是ZPM已经用完了，没用了
事实上，不完全这样
- The ZPM has been depleted. It's of no use.
- Actually, that's not entirely true.
记得上次我们用的时候，ZPM还留有能量
以使我们能再次回到亚特兰蒂斯
The last time we used it, the ZPM had to establish
and maintain a wormhole back to Atlantis.
这次，我们所要做的就是用足够的能量搭起一个
最普通的连接
This time around, all we need for it to do is to have
enough energy to establish the briefest of connections
我计算的结果是，整个只需3.5微秒
By my calculations, approximately 3.5 microseconds.
看起来时间还不够啊
将军，记得上次我们去M5S224星球的时候
- That hardly seems like enough time to accomplish--
- General, when we first set foot on M5S224,
在虫洞关闭之前
我检测到能量场的变化
before the wormhole shut down,
I picked up fluctuations in the energy field.
假设那是残余能量所引起的话
I just assumed that was an effect of
the gate's residual energy signature,
不过后来我觉得，那些能量不足以引起
能量场这么大的变化
but having given it some thought, I realized
that can't account for such sizable variances,
剩下的只有一个解释
which leaves only one possible explanation.
在我们到达的时候，星际之门一定又被补充了
新的能量
The gate must have been energized on our arrival,
也就是说，出去的时候需要能量
meaning it doesn't just draw
power on outgoing wormholes,
返回的时候也需要能量
but on incoming wormholes as well.
我们所要做的只是搭起一个连接
All we have to do is make a connection.
3.5微秒，这是搭建
3.5 microseconds, that's
the minimal amount of time it requires
所需的最少时间
to confirm a lock before
the gate automatically kicks in,
接着它就会从空气中汲取能量
维持自身的运作了
drawing power from the atmosphere
to maintain the wormhole.
请原谅我，博士
你说的这一切听起来很牵强
You'll forgive me, doctor.
This all seems a little farfetched.
你可以把它想象成打长途电话那样
Think of it like making a long-distance call
在电话的那一头会有人来接的
to someone you know is going to accept the charges.
你所要做的只是拨一下号而已
All you have to do is dial.
对不起，博士
I'm sorry, doctor.
唉，让我试试，你不会遭受任何损失的，对吧？
Well, you're not going to lose
anything by letting me try, are you?
我所要做的只是要实验几次罢了
All I want to do is run a couple of tests.
好吧，我会把ZPM送到实验室的
All right. I'll have the ZPM delivered to the lab.
谢谢
Thank you.
Weir博士，没想到你会来这儿
Dr. Weir, I wasn't expecting to see you.
我一直在想最近发生的事情
I've been thinking about what happened.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道我们是遇到了一些挫折
I know it's a bit of a setback,
但是我不认为我们应就此放弃
but I don't think we should give up just yet.
如果我们能将飞船修好的话
If we can get the prometheus repaired--
飞船受到了极大的损坏
The prometheus was severely damaged.
我们已失去20个人了
We lost 20 crew members.
她以后再也飞不起来了
She won't be flying again any time soon.
我们还可以找仙宫座的来帮忙啊
So we ask the Asgard for one of their ships.
他们要是能帮助的话，肯定会来的
Well, I'm sure that when the Asgard
are in a position to help, they will.
将军，我回到地球的原因是我向他们保证过
我肯定会回去的
General, I only came to Earth because
I was assured I'd be able to get back.
现在，我不打算放弃我的探险队
Now, I am not about to abandon my expedition team.
我会尽最大所能
但是我无法向你保证什么
I'll see what I can do,
but I'm not making any promises.
你得跟别人看看我的情况啊
You've got to talk to somebody about this for me.
对不起了
Look, I'm sorry.
如果这是你收到的命令的话，跟我就没有什么关系了
If those are the orders you received,
it's out of my hands.
我简直不能忍受这份工作，这太无聊了
If there's one thing I can't abide, it's sloppy work.
如果你的人好好核实一下实验结果的话
If your people won't double-check their results,
就不会发生这样的事 了
then there's no point in keeping them on the team.
McKay博士
你好，上尉
- Dr. McKay.
- Yes, Lieutenant.
我被调职了
I'm being transferred.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
不，你不明白
No, you don't understand.
我和父母待在一起
还没几天
I was chillin' with my parents,
just having a good time,
就有人要来替换我
and some sergeant shows up with new orders for me.
我想回到亚特兰蒂斯
I want to go back to Atlantis,
而他们却想把我送往南极
and they want to ship me back to Antarctica.
上尉，不知你是否知道
Lieutenant, do you know something that I don't,
上次我检查的时候
飞船就已收到了严重的损坏
because the last time I checked,
the Prometheus was critically damaged,
我们所拥有的在ZPM连一台
汽车音响都开不了
and the only ZPM in our possession
didn't have the power to run a car stereo.
我想你会找到别的方法的
I just thought you'd be trying to find another way.
上尉，没有别的方法
There is no other way, Lieutenant.
你得准备好面对现实吧
You're just going to have to deal with it.
谢谢
Thank you.
待在这儿难道不好吗？
Would it be so bad if you had to stay?
对不起，Simon
I'm sorry, Simon.
我知道这对你很不公平
I know none of this is fair to you.
我知道我很难与人类史上最伟大
的发现相提并论
It is tough to compete with
the greatest adventure in human history.
我并不怪你离开
I don't blame you for going.
谢谢
Thank you...
可是我仍然感到内疚
But I still feel guilty.
现在我对回来感到内疚了
And now I feel guilty about being back.
因为那些你留在那儿的人
Because of the people you left behind?
不是，我应该留在亚特兰蒂斯的
No. I should have stayed at Atlantis.
应该只让Sheppard少校一个人回来
Major Sheppard should have been the one to go.
哦，天
Oh, yeah.
和我走的时候一样
Just like I left it.
一个人住这么大地方太空了点
So much space for just one person.
呃，男孩子吗，就得这样啊
Well, a guy's got to have a lot of space.
我想应该还有点......
I bet there's still...
太好了
Perfect.
这个不错，冰的
Nice and cold.
这是
And this is...
这叫啤酒
It's called beer.
这些都是用来
Is all this...
娱乐的吗？
For recreation?
是啊，很多你意想不到的东西我这儿都有，对吧？
Yeah, I got pretty much everything
you can imagine, don't I?
怎么了？
What is it?
我又在想了......
I was just thinking again...
Weir博士和其他人在亚特兰蒂斯的情况
How Dr. Weir and everyone else on Atlantis...
当然
Of course.
我敢肯定她没事的
I am sure she is fine.
而且他们所有的人都没事的
As I am sure they are all fine.
是啊
Yeah.
我也这么想
I'm sure.
你们还没有得出实验结果吗？
You people have those test results for me yet?
还需要一点时间
We need more time.
你说什么？让我看看你们得出些什么结论
What are you talking about?
Let me see what you've got.
等等
Wait a minute.
这是什么，你开玩笑吗？
What is this, some kind of a joke?
我跟你说了，还需要点时间
I told you, we need more time.
这些根本没用
These don't even make any sense.
我们认为ZPM已经没有足够的能量来
开启虫洞了
We don't think the ZPM has enough
power to open the wormhole.
可是，你难道不知道你写了些什么吗？
Well, you wouldn't know that from this, would you?
一堆乱七八糟的东西
This might as well say, "bing, tiddle, tiddle, bong."
都是垃圾
It's complete gibberish.
你给我出去，我来做
Look, get out of here. I'll do it.
滚
Go.
你简直就是在搞笑
You've got to be kidding me.
博士，感谢你又回来了
Thank you for coming in again, Doctor.
我的要求有没有回应？
Has there been a response to my request?
事实上，我们不打算从仙宫座活得任何帮助
Actually, we won't be needing any help from the Asgard.
McKay博士似乎已经找到一个解决方法了
It turns out Dr. McKay has found a solution
可以重新开启虫洞，让我们回到天马座
that will enable us to open a wormhole back to Pegasus.
他已经？
He has?
为什么我还不知道？
Why wasn't I informed?
博士，亚特兰蒂斯的探险任务被重新评估了
Doctor, the Atlantis mission has been reassessed.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
就你们带回的有关幽灵的信息来看
In light of the intelligence you
brought us concerning the Wraith,
我们一致认为亚特兰蒂斯星球上的生物应该是
极具侵略性的东西
it's been decided that the Atlantis
presence should be military.
我们的盟友也这么认为吗?
Our allies have agreed to this?
是的
They did.
一旦Mckay博士重新搭起虫洞
As soon as Dr. McKay can establish a wormhole,
我们打算派支部队过去
we intend to send reinforcements,
同时还要再指派一名指挥官一同前往
along with a new commanding officer.
博士，真对不起，你已经被解职了
I'm sorry, doctor, but you've
been relieved of your duties.
唉，等会
Okay, wait a minute.
我并没有说那里有外星人的军事武装
I am not saying that there shouldn't
be an increased military presence,
可是原来的任务还是要继续进行下去的
but the mission must remain the same...
我肯定Sheppard少校若是听到你刚才说的话
他会告诉你......
And I'm sure if Major Sheppard
were here he'd tell you--
我们已经和Sheppard少校沟通过了
We've spoken to Major Sheppard.
他一小时前刚打电话过来
想看看你进展如何
He dialed in about an hour ago
to check on your progress.
我们将当前形式跟他说了
We informed him of the situation,
他也同意我们的判断
and he agrees with our assessment.
他不会这么做的，将军
He wouldn't do that, General.
我很了解John Sheppard
I know John Sheppard.
很显然，你并不想你所想象的那样了解他，博士
Apparently, you don't know him
as well as you thought, Doctor.
Sheppard 少校坚决同意
Major Sheppard stated categorically
这是确保任务安全完成的唯一方法
it's the only way to ensure
the security of the project.
我们出去吧
Let's get out of here.
为什么？
Why?
你想看看地面是吧，就在那儿
You want to see Earth, right? It's out there.
我想你该在家住段时间，看看老朋友
I thought you would want to spend
time in your home, visit with friends.
好主意
There is an idea.
嘿
Hey!
Mitch
Mitch.
Dex
Dex.
你真的认为你在这个城市走一圈
我们会看不到你吗
You didn't really think you could pass
through town without seeing us, did you, Shep?
你想不想让我们进来啊？
So you going to invite us in or what?
哦，当然了，这到底怎么了？
Yeah, sure. What the hell?
你好，我是Dex
Hi. I'm Dex.
这是什么？
What is this?
有没有什么问题？
Is there a problem?
Elizabeth
Elizabeth.
Rodney，我得和你谈谈
能等会吗？
- Rodney, I need to talk to you.
- Can it wait?
不行，这里始终不对劲
No. Something is very wrong here.
我在检测ZPM
I've run a diagnostic on the ZPM.
这些是我得来的实验结果
These are the results I keep getting back.
Rodney，我不是科学家
I'm not a scientist, Rodney.
没人是科学家，或者说在这儿
物理学的各种法则，定律都他妈的失效了
Neither is anyone else, or they'd have noticed
the laws of physics seem to have flown out the window.
也许是你的设备出了问题吧
Maybe there's a problem with your equipment.
我检查过，没问题的
I checked. It's fine.
这样的话，要是你没能得出正确的结果的话
那便是你的错了
Look, if your solution doesn't work,
it's not your fault.
我们只得接受我们无法回去的事实了
We'll just have to accept
the fact that we can't go back.
什么？
What?
我们的人被敌人火力压住了
So our boys were pinned down.
我们最终设法通过了那座桥
So hotshot takes his chopper over this bridge--
我们还想跟在他后面呢
And we were supposed to follow him.
可那是不可能的，我当时正骑着一只鹰
在敌人的坦克上面飞呢
Well, there's no way I'm flying a blackhawk
over a bridge with enemy tanks on it--
等等，你说什么来着？
Wait, with what on it?
坦克
哦，是吗
- Tanks.
- You're welcome.
你这家伙还真有趣
I still love that, man.
是啊，他真幽默啊
Yeah, that was, uh... priceless.
可是......
But, uh...
我们最终得让队伍通过那里，对吧，Shep？
We got that special ops team
out of there, didn't we, Shep?
是的
Yes, we did.
我跟你说吧，除非我们都长翅膀才行
I'll tell you what, that was some flying, Shep.
快看，这是谁送比萨来了
Well, look who's in the pizza-delivery business.
先生
No, sir.
我只是在送货的途中得知你回来了
I just caught the guy on the way up.
我刚想到你
干嘛不过来坐坐？
I was just thinking about you.
Why don't you come in?
看起来我们正......
Looks like we...
开着晚会
Are having a party.
谢谢
Thanks.
我的比萨
I've got pizza.
我被解职了
I've been relieved of my command.
哦，很抱歉听到你这个消息
Oh. Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
他们要派军队去亚特兰蒂斯
They're going to militarize Atlantis.
真有趣
Interesting.
不过这迟早会发生的
Well, it was bound to happen sooner or later.
什么，你也认同他们的作法？
What, so you're just okay with this?
Elizabrth，你一直对他们说什么鬼魂的事情
你想他们会怎么做？
Elizabeth, how did you expect them to react
when you told them about the Wraith?
可是至少他们得让我参加啊
At the very least, I thought I'd be kept in the loop.
你看来有些神经质了，干嘛不回家
和Simon好好待在一起在在？
You're just being paranoid.
Go spend time with Simon.
Simon？
Simon?
是啊，他对你难道不重要吗？
Yes, he's important to you, isn't he?
当然
Yes.
我真的不记得曾跟你讲过他的事情
I just don't remember ever telling you that.
哦，我怎么知道的呢？
Well, how else would I have known?
我们不知道该想些什么？
We didn't know what to think.
我的意思是，这些家伙
I mean, this guy was supposedly
可能是阿富汗最残忍的人
one of the most ruthless warlords in afghanistan,
可能突然间他们还会做到我们的饭桌前
and suddenly, he just sits down at our table.
老兄，你得听听这个故事
Sir, you got to hear this story--
中尉，当时我在场
Yeah, I was there, Lieutenant...
哦，是吗，你记得了
Oh, yeah, you remember.
看起来他是想好好锻炼一下自己的英语啊
Turns out he just wants to practice his english.
Shep花了半夜和这个家伙聊天
Shep spent half the night talking to this guy.
真有趣
That was funny.
他甚至不会让你得闲上厕所，还记得吗？
He wouldn't even let you get up
to go to the bathroom, remember?
两天后，你们在Kabul就战死了
And two days later, you guys were killed outside Kabul.
让我看看是否能让你明白，好吗？
Let me see if I can make you understand, okay?
这些结果不仅仅证明了ZPM无法运作了
These results don't just say the ZPM won't work.
而且还证明所有的自然定律都不起作用了
They say this reality isn't
governed by any natural laws.
就像通过一个显微镜去观察一个细胞
却发现在细胞中有成千上万只老鼠在跳舞
It's like looking through a microscope at a cell
culture and seeing a thousand dancing hamsters!
这是不可能的
it's impossible!
Rodney，你得安静下来
Rodney, you need to calm down.
不不不，我心里现在简直烦透了
No, no, what I need to do now is get very agitated,
因为我意识到这所有的一切都是假的
because what I'm realizing
is that all of this is a lie.
这个，这个
This... And this...
还有这个
And this!
你说什么？
What are you saying?
直升机当时去救你们的时候出事了
Their chopper took an RPG when
it touched down for a medevac.
你们不可能存活下来
There was barely enough left
to bring back for a military funeral.
你说什么？
What?
你们已经死去很多年了
You guys have been dead for years.
真的很高兴能在见到你们
Don't get me wrong, it's really nice seeing you...
还有你，Wstson夫人
And you too, Mrs. Watson.
先生，我不知道
她是我六年级时的老师
- Sir, I don't...
- She was my sixth grade teacher...
还有
And...
我不记得你叫什么
但是我相信我们以前从未在一起过
I don't even remember your name,
but I remember you wouldn't even date me!
Shep，我想我们得带你去看看医生
Shep, I think we should take you to see a doctor.
哦，是吗？
Oh, really?
哦，你的行为真是有点怪
Yeah, you're acting pretty strange.
我的行为有点怪，嗯？
Oh, I'm acting strange, huh?
少尉！
Major!
现在，你知道我指的是什么了吧？
Now, do you see what I mean?
我所认识的Rodney McKay决不会无条件同意
Okay, the Rodney McKay I know would never accept
派部队去亚特兰蒂斯的
the militarization of Atlantis
without putting up a fight.
我相信Sheppard少校也决不会同意这么做的
I don't think Major Sheppard would agree to it either.
至少在跟我提过此事之前不会这么做的
At least not without speaking to me about it first.
Elizabeth，你也别太认真了好不好
Elizabeth, you shouldn't take it personally.
我的意思是，把它想象成一件好事
I mean, think of it like a blessing.
你有自己的生活
你现在无法回去了
You have a life.
You can get back to it now.
不，我不会就这么算了的
No. I'm not buying this anymore.
你究竟是谁？
Who are you really?
我是谁？你什么意思？
Who am I? What do you mean?
你开枪打我！
You shot me!
你已经死了
You're already dead.
先生，请把枪给我
Sir, give me the...
中尉，现在我对你也开始怀疑你了
I'm beginning to have my doubts
about you too, Lieutenant.
我不会想当然就当然了
I wouldn't put them to a test.
现在，你们赶紧告诉我这儿到底
他妈的是怎么回事？
Now, somebody explain to me
what the hell is going on here.
Wire博士
Dr. Weir.
好了，别在撒谎了
Okay, no more lies.
这究竟是怎么回事？
What is this?
What's happening to me?
没有必要在骗你了
There's no point in deluding you any longer.
现在你知道了
Now you know.
Rodney到哪儿去了
Where's Rodney?
真正的McKay博士和他的队员们都
The real Dr. McKay and the rest of his team
生活在各自的幻想世界里
reside in their own illusory worlds.
我想见他们，请带我去
I want to see them. Please.
怎么了？
What happened?
我把你们各自从幻想世界带回来了
I drew you together from your fractured realities.
刚才我手里还拿着啤酒呢
No, I'm talking about the beer I had.
Sheppard少校刚才也发现了事实的真相
Major Sheppard discovered the truth some time ago.
是吗？
He did?
在过去的11个月中，我在在南极做个项目呢
Home for the last 11 months,
has been a research base in Antarctica.
尽管我以前真的曾这么想过，可是......
although... I did dream about
a bachelor pad like that, but--
Sheppard少校似乎有着独特的能力来操控
Major Sheppard seemed uniquely capable
想象的世界
of manipulating his own fabricated reality.
一想到我这些假想的经历，真想狠狠地踢自己一脚
When I think of the scenarios
I could've thought up, I'd kick myself.
你们所经历的这些经历是你们脑海
中曾经出现过的思维的片断
The realities you experienced were
fabrications of your own minds.
因为你尚无地球上生活的经历
Since you had no memories of Earth to draw from,
所以你便加入了Shepard少校的幻想之中
you shared in Major Sheppard's illusion.
我想那肯定是你
I thought that was you.
真遗憾你们这么快就苏醒过来了
It is unfortunate that you all became aware so quickly.
不过，你们仍可以选择一个幻想的场景
Hower, you may now create a fabricated reality
以便度过余生
of your own choosing in which to live
out the remainder of your lives.
你说什么？
What?
那对我们没用的
That's not going to work for us.
恐怕这件事由不得你来控制
I'm afraid the matter is beyond your control.
那好
Well...
我们会想出办法来打倒你
We'll find a way to fight you.
那简直就是不可能的，少校
That would be quite impossible, Major.
即使你们处于同一个幻境之中
Even now you are simply
experiencing a shared fabrication.
你们最好各自过各自的生活
It will be best if you try
to make a life for yourselves.
这根本不是什么生活！
This isn't life!
你想让我们怎么办，要装一辈子傻子？
What do you want us to do, just pretend?
对不起，我能做到的就这些了
I'm sorry, but that's all I can offer you.
你等会
Wait.
为什么你要这么做？
Why would you do this?
为了保护我们自己
To protect ourselves.
防备我们？
From us?
我们不想伤害任何人
We did not intend to harm anyone.
不像你们，我们是以一种能量的，无形的形式存在
Unlike you, we exist in a
non-corporeal form susceptible
于这个星球上，我们不能受到任何毁灭性的影响
to the destructive effects
of the Stargate on our home-world.
什么毁灭性的影响？
What destructive effects?
这就是为什么能量表显示，这里有
生命的迹象
So the energy readings, they were life signs.
你活在雾中
You were in the mist.
我们就是雾，每次星际之门打开的时候
我们中就会有很多人死去
We are the mist, and every time
the gate is activated, lives are lost.
很多次，探险者们来了又走
根本无视我们的存在
Over time, explorers have come and gone,
completely unaware of our existence.
为了安全起见，我们必须付出牺牲
Sacrifices are made to ensure our secrecy,
你们一来便引起了我们的警惕
but when you came back, we grew concerned.
为了得知你们的想法，我们除了进入你们的
大脑之外别无选择
To learn your intentions,
we had no choice but to enter your minds.
当我们得知你们要做什么的时候
When we discovered what you were about to do,
我们被迫采取防护措施
we were forced to take preventive measures.
但是你刚才说让别人来了又走
But you just said you'd let others come and go.
为什么不让我们也这样做呢？
Why not allow us to do the same?
你们回家的想法太强烈了
Your desire to return to
your home-world was too strong.
要搭建通往其他星系的大门所需的能量
The amount of energy required to gate to another galaxy
将会使数以百万计的生灵丧命
would have killed millions of our kind.
所以当我们试图打开大门的时候——
So when we dialed the gate--
你们从未打开大门
你们只是假想你们打开了
You never dialed the gate.
You just imagined you did.
即使现在，你们仍在这个星球的表面上躺着
不省人事
You are unconscious, even now, on the planet's surface.
那么，刚才发生的一切都是假的了？
So none of this is real?
那个漂亮的黑色肤色的女人
我本该知道的，怎么能够从......
The cute brunette. Of course, I should've known.
I mean, how do you go from...
“你是头猪，可是我喜欢你的猫”一直聊到
“我很想你”
"you're a pig, but I like your cat" to "I missed you"?
我们没有你们的思维那么复杂
We lacked a sophisticated understanding of your world.
所以，我们为你们创造的幻境
还是有所缺陷的
As a result, the illusions we created
from your thoughts were ultimately flawed.
死人就不会制造麻烦了
The dead people were a dead giveaway.
死人
Dead people.
你说什么?
What were you doing?
如果你提早告诉我们，我的意思是，也许我们可以......
哦，等等
- If you had just told us, I mean, maybe we could...
- Whoa, wait.
我想起什么了
I just realized something.
你刚才说我们那不省人事的身躯
还在这个星球的表面上
You're saying that our unconscious
bodies are still on the planet.
是的
Yes.
可是，我们需要食物，我们需要水
我的意思是，我们需要事物
Yeah, well, so we need food. We need water.
I mean, we need food.
他的意思是要让我们处于这种状态下
便会活不长久
What he's saying is we won't live long in this state.
所以我建议你们要好好利用剩下来的时间啊
Then I suggest you make the most
of the time you have left.
为了就你自己却要杀了我们
You're killing us in order to save yourselves.
是为了拯救数百万个我们同类
In order to save millions of our kind.
相信你要是我的话也会这么做的
I believe you would do the same.
如果我们没回去的话
我们的朋友会来找我们的
If we do not go back,
our friends will come looking for us.
你们其他人？
Others of your kind?
他们会出现的
They'll show up.
你打算怎么做，也杀了他们?
What are you going to do, kill them too?
还回来更多的
And more will come.
总有一天，他们会知道怎么进入
这个星际之门
One day, they'll figure out how to access the Gate.
到时，数百万的你们同类仍然会死的
Then millions of your kind will die.
我们从不会落下战友的
We don't leave people behind,
要是你是真的Hammond将军的话
你早就知道这一点了
and if you were really General Hammond,
you'd know that.
但是如果你允许我们离开这里
But if you allow us to leave here,
我们保证我们永远都不会再来这儿的
永远不会
we promise we will never return, ever.
你将不必害怕我们
我向你保证
You will not have to fear us ever again.
I give you my word.
你现在一心想着回家，当然会这么说了
How can you make such a promise
when you so desire to return home?
确实
Sure,
我们是想回家
we'd like to go home.
可是我们并不想为此目的
去杀死数百万你们同类
We're not willing to kill
millions of your kind to do it.
你已经在我们的大脑中了
现在已经在我们的大脑中了
You've been in our heads.
You're in our heads right now
你应该知道我们是认真的
You should know we mean that.
我明白
I understand.
我并不想发表相反的意见
因为这可能有点......你知道
I don't mean to sound negative,
because that would be, you know, so not me...
你怎么知道这不是个骗局呢？
But how do we know this isn't a double fake-out?
我的意思是，我们怎么知道这是不是真的
I mean, how do we know that this is--
这是你们的真实世界
This is your reality.
我向你们保证
You have my word.
我饿了
I'm starving.
他说的对
He's got to be right.
我在想我们出来多久了
I wonder how long we've been out.
我得水晶球从DHD中取出来
几分钟就可以了
I need to get the control crystal out of the DHD.
Shouldn't take more than a few minutes.
我帮你一把
I'll give you a hand.
谢谢你相信我们
Thank you for trusting us.
Rodney，小心点
Rodney, be careful with that.
我要确保我们能回到家
I want to make sure we can get back home.
你指的是亚特兰蒂斯？
You mean Atlantis?
我想她就是这么想的
I think that's what she meant.
我怎么知道她不想让我玩个花招
让我连通去地球的通道
How do I know she wasn't suggesting
we pull a double fake and dial Earth?
别玩花招了
Forget the double fake.
快把那该死的水晶球拿出来
Get the damn crystal.
我会这么做的
I'll do the dial-out.